Guide to the William Martin Religious Right research collection, 1975-2000 MS 537
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
William Martin Religious Right research collection
1975-2000
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Martin, William C. (William Curtis)
MS 537
130 Linear Feet 130 boxes
This collection consists of research materials compiled by William Martin, Rice University professor of sociology, during the course of his research on the Christian religious right in the United States, as well as fundamentalists, fundamentalist education, evangelists such as Billy Graham, and other aspects of conservative Christian organizations. The materials consists of correspondence, notes, videos, transcriptions of video interviews, pamphlets, and books.
Biographical Sketch
William Martin (Ph.D., Harvard, 1969), is the Harry and Hazel Chavanne Emeritus Professor of Religion and Public Policy in the Department of Sociology at Rice. Since his retirement from teaching in June 2005, he serves as the Chavanne Senior Fellow for Religion and Public Policy at the James A. Baker III Institute for Public Policy at Rice. His areas of specialization include religion, criminology, and issues related to drug use and drug policy. He has been a professor at Rice since 1968.
Professor Martin's recent research and writing have focused in two areas: 1) religious fundamentalism and its impact in the political arena, in the United States and elsewhere; and 2) issues related to drugs, with particular emphasis on ways to reduce the harms associated with drug abuse and drug policy. In this connection, he has organized and chaired a series of programs at conferences at the Baker Institute dealing with these issues.
After several years of experience as a boy preacher, Bill Martin attended Abilene (Texas) Christian University, where he received B.A. (1958) and M.A. (1960) degrees in Biblical Studies and taught for one year as a graduate assistant. He then attended Harvard Divinity School, where he received the B.D. degree in 1963. In 1969, he received his Ph.D. from Harvard, in a program known as Religion and Society, a joint effort between the Divinity School and the Department of Social Relations. His dissertation, Christians in Conflict: The Role of the Clergy in Racial Conflict in Rochester, New York, was prepared under the direction of Harvey Cox, Joseph Fichter, and Thomas Pettigrew. At Harvey Cox's suggestion, he submitted an article based on his thesis to The Atlantic Monthly, which published it as the lead article in its December 1967 issue. Flushed with the pleasure of having his work read by large numbers, Bill Martin began to follow an unusual career path of publishing mainly in high-quality magazines such as The Atlantic, Harper's, Esquire, and Texas Monthly, for which he wrote a three-year monthly series of articles on Texas churches that led to his being the subject of a "60 Minutes" segment in September 1979.
During the 1970s and 1980s, Professor Martin concentrated mainly on religious broadcasters and was one of the first academicians to give serious attention to what came to be known as the Electronic Church. At the end of the 1970s, this led naturally to increased attention to fundamentalist involvement in politics and the rise of the movement known as the Religious Right. This work culminated, after dozens of articles, in his writing "With God on Our Side: The Rise of the Religious Right in America" (Broadway Books, 1996), the companion volume to the PBS mini-series of the same name and for which he served as chief consultant. A revised edition of both the book and the video series appeared in the summer of 2005. His writings on various aspects of evangelical and fundamentalist religion also led to his being given the opportunity write "A Prophet with Honor: The Billy Graham Story" (William Morrow, 1991), regarded as the most authoritative biography of the famed evangelist. An updated version of this book is in progress [as of July 2998]. In addition to these historical and sociological publications, Professor Martin also wrote "My Prostate and Me: Dealing with Prostate Cancer" (Caddell and Davies, 1994), an account of his own successful bout with this disease. As a result, he has appeared on more than 150 radio and television programs to discuss prostate cancer and regularly counsels with men and families touched by the disease.
More recently, as noted above, Bill Martin has taken an active role in the Baker Institute, organizing and chairing programs and conferences on the impact of religion, particularly various forms of fundamentalism, on public policy, and on ways to reduce the harms associated with drug abuse and drug policy. Many of these papers are available on the Baker Institute website.
Bill Martin received a number of teaching awards during his years as a professor, including the George R. Brown Life Honor Award, which made him ineligible for most additional awards given by Rice. At age sixteen, he decided to become a college professor as a consequence of exposure to particularly inspiring and dedicated teachers he encountered during his freshman year in college. As he enters partial retirement after more than thirty-seven years at Rice, he still regards it as a fine decision.
Recent Publications
* "With God on Their Side: Religion and American Foreign Policy ," Chapter 11 in Hugh Heclo and Wilfred M. McClay, Refurnishing the Public Square: Religion and Public Policy in Twentieth-Century America, (Woodrow Wilson Center/Johns Hopkins University Press, 2003). * "Amen," Texas Monthly, December 2002. Billy Graham's October 2002 Metroplex Mission. * "Embracing the Lite" in Arvind Sharma, editor, Religion in a Secular City: Essays in Honor of Harvey Cox. Trinity Press International, 2001. * "With God on Their Side," Georgetown Journal of International Affairs, Winter/Spring 2000, pp. 7-14. * "Billy Graham," Christian History, 65 (Vol. XIX, No. 1), Spring 2000. Pp. 12-16 * "The Christian Right and American Foreign Policy," Foreign Policy, Spring 1999, pp. 66-80.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of research materials compiled by William Martin, Rice University professor of sociology, during the course of his research on the Christian religious right in the United States, as well as fundamentalists, fundamentalist education, evangelists such as Billy Graham, and other aspects of conservative Christian organizations. The materials consists of correspondence, notes, videos, transcriptions of video interviews, pamphlets, and books.
Oral history interviews on videotape and transcribed into print form make just over half of the collection. The video was recorded by Lumiere Productions in New York City in 1995 - January 1996, and transcribed primarily by Wordprint Studios largely as research material for Martin's book With God on Our Side.
Restrictions on Access
This material is open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Provenance
This material was donated by Prof. Bill Martin.
Arrangement
This collection consists of
Missing Title
Series I: Videos, interviews and transcripts, 1995-1996 (Boxes 1-76)
Series II: Subject files, 1978-1996 (Boxes 77-91)
Series III: Broadcasters and Broadcasting, 1975-1978 and undated (Boxes 92 -98)
Series IV: Evangelists, 1975-1990 and undated (Boxes 99-121)
Series V: Research on Evangelical Education, 1990-2000 (Boxes 122-124)
Series VI: Publications (Boxes 125-127)
Series VII: Addendum (Boxes 128-130)
Bibliography
"With God on our side: the rise of the religious right in America"/ William Martin. "Apocalypse soon [videorecording]: the contemporary significance of biblical prophecy" / William Martin."A prophet with honor: the Billy Graham story / William Martin."Christians in conflict" / William Martin.
Index Terms
Subjects
Religion; Christianity and politics; Church and state -- United States; Conservatism -- United States; Religious fundamentalism; Evangelists -- United States -- Biography; Television in religion; Millennialism; Politics and government
Document Types
audiotapes; transcripts; clippings (information artifacts); videotapes; pamphlets
Subjects (Persons)
Swaggart, Jimmy; Robertson, Pat; Martin, William C. (William Curtis); Falwell, Jerry; Dobson, Ed; Hatfield, Mark O.; Graham, Billy
- Series I: Videos, interviews and transcripts (Boxes 1-76), 1995-1996
  - 000.001.5 Sacred Lies Civil Truths, 1993; VHS (Box 1, Folder -)
  - 000.003.5 Promise Keepers "Seize the Moment", 1994; VHS (Box 1, Folder -)
  - 000.003.5 Promise Keepers Promotional Material, undated; Betamax (Box 1, Folder -)
  - 000.006.5 Youth For Christ - Changing the Future…Today, undated; VHS (Box 1, Folder -)
  - 000.006.5 Youth For Christ - Changing the Future…Today, undated; Betamax (Box 1, Folder -)
  - 000.007.5 People for the American Way - "Pat Robertson: In His Own Words", undated; VHS (Box 1, Folder -)
  - 000.008.8 With God on Our Side - Pat Hart's Answering Machine, undated; Beta (Box 1, Folder -)
  - 001.001.4 Jimmy Carter Remarks at Town Meetings in New Hampshire and Maine; 1976 Campaign Footage, undated; Betamax (Box 1, Folder -)
  - 001.002.4 Jimmy Carter Library, undated; Beta (Box 1, Folder -)
  - 001.002.4 Jimmy Carter Library - Inaugural MLK Sr. "Call the Prez" Pageant for Peace, June 1978; BetaMax (Box 1, Folder -)
  - 001.003.4 Criswell: Carter; Criswell: Taxation; Criswell: I Like That; It's Time to Pray America; Gerald Ford at Abilene Christian University, undated; BetaMax (Box 1, Folder -)
  - 001.003.4 Criswell: Carter [retransfer], undated; Beta (Box 1, Folder -)
  - 001.004.1 With God on Our Side - "White House Conference on Family", September 20, 1995; BetaCam SP (Box 1, Folder -)
  - 001.004.2 Jimmy Carter's White House Conference on Family, July 20, 1979 (Box 1, Folder -)
  - 001.005.1 With God on Our Side - "Religious Broadcasters Convention", September 20, 1995; BetaCam SP (Box 1, Folder -)
  - 001.005.2 Jimmy Carter Speech to NRB; "Religious Broadcasters Convention", January 21, 1980; Beta (Box 1, Folder -)
  - 001.006.1 With God on Our Side - "319", September 20, 1995; BetaCam SP (Box 1, Folder -)
  - 001.006.2 Jimmy Carter Speech to Baltimore WHCF, undated; Betamax (Box 1, Folder -)
  - 001.007.1 Jimmy Carter at Town Meeting in Pittsburgh, October 29, 1980; BetaCam SP (Box 1, Folder -)
  - 001.007.2 Jimmy Carter Remarks at Town Meeting in Pittsburgh, October 29, 1980 [January 30, 1996] Betamax (Box 1, Folder -)
  - 001.008.1 Jimmy Carter Remarks at Town Meeting in Memphis, October 31, 1980; Betacam SP (Box 1, Folder -)
  - 001.008.2 Jimmy Carter Remarks at Town Meeting in Memphis, October 31, 1980; BetaMax (Box 2, Folder -)
  - 001.009.1 Jimmy Carter 1976, 1976; BetaCam SP (Box 2, Folder -)
  - 001.009.2 Jimmy Carter 1976, 1976; BetaMax (Box 2, Folder -)
  - 001.010.1 Jimmy Carter at Nashua High School Town Meeting, February 18, 1978; BetaCam SP (Box 2, Folder -)
  - 001.010.2 Jimmy Carter at Nashua High School Town Meeting, February 18, 1978; BetaMax (Box 2, Folder -)
  - 001.011.1 1976 Campaign Tapes, 1976; Beta (Box 2, Folder -)
  - 001.011.2 1976 Campaign Tapes, 1976; Beta (Box 2, Folder -)
  - 001.012.1 Jimmy Carter Speech to National Conference of Catholic Charities, 1976 [January 30, 1996]; Beta (Box 2, Folder -)
  - 001.012.2 1976 Campaign Tapes (Part 1 of 2), 1976; Beta (Box 2, Folder -)
  - 001.012.2 1976 Campaign Tapes (Part 2 of 2), 1976; Beta (Box 2, Folder -)
  - 002.001.4 Gerald Ford at Southern Baptist Convention, 1974; Beta (Box 2, Folder -)
  - 002.002.4 Jimmy Carter Interview with Bill Sumners (Copy 1 of 2), September 1991; Beta (Box 2, Folder -)
  - 002.002.4 Jimmy Carter Interview with Bill Sumners (Copy 2 of 2), undated; Beta (Box 2, Folder -)
  - 002.003.4 Jimmy Carter Sunday School Class (Copy 1 of 2), September 1991; Beta (Box 2, Folder -)
  - 002.003.4 Jimmy Carter Sunday School Class (Copy 2 of 2), September 1991; Beta (Box 2, Folder -)
  - 002.004.5 Criswell Sermon at 1985 Pastor's Conference in Dallas, 1986; VHS (Box 2, Folder -)
  - 002.005.2 Bailey Smith at Southern Baptist Convention, undated; Beta (Box 2, Folder -)
  - 002.005.5 Bailey Smith at Southern Baptist Convention, undated; VHS (Box 2, Folder -)
  - 002.006.1 Excerpt from 1976 Southern Baptist Convention in Norfolk, VA, 1976; Beta (Box 2, Folder -)
  - 003.001.4 Dr. Jerry Falwell "I Love America"/ Old Time Gospel Hour (Beta, DVD), May 10, 1994 (Box 2, Folder -)
  - 003.002.1 Footage from LBN Tape Library, undated; BetaCam SP (Box 2, Folder -)
  - 003.002.2 Footage from LBN Tape Library (Tape 1 of 4), undated; Beta (Box 3, Folder -)
  - 003.003.1 Footage from LBN Tape Library (Tape 2 of 4), undated; BetaCam SP (Box 3, Folder -)
  - 003.003.2 Footage from LBN Tape Library (Tape 2 of 4: Part 1), undated; Beta (Box 3, Folder -)
  - 003.003.2 Footage from LBN Tape Library (Tape 2 of 4: Part 2), undated; Beta (Box 3, Folder -)
  - 003.004.1 Footage from LBN Tape Library (Tape 3 of 4), undated; Beta (Box 3, Folder -)
  - 003.004.2 Footage from LBN Tape Library (Tape 3 of 4), undated; Beta (Box 3, Folder -)
  - 003.005.2 Footage from LBN Tape Library (Tape 4 of 4), undated; Beta (Box 3, Folder -)
  - 003.006.1 Old Time Gospel Hour - Jerry Falwell "The Truth About AIDS", January 31, 1993; BetaCam SP (Box 3, Folder -)
  - 003.006.2 Old Time Gospel Hour - Jerry Falwell "The Truth About AIDS", undated; Beta (Box 3, Folder -)
  - 003.006.5 Liberty University Presents "The Spirit of Liberty", undated; VHS (Box 3, Folder -)
  - 004.001.4 Nixon Resignation, Gerald Ford Swearing In (Tape 1 of 2), June 6, 1994; Beta (Box 3, Folder -)
  - 004.002.4 Nixon Resignation, Gerald Ford Swearing In (Tape 2 of 2), June 6, 1994; Beta (Box 3, Folder -)
  - 004.003.4 Richard Nixon in Charlotte, NC in honor of Billy Graham (Tape 1 of 2), June 6, 1994 (Box 3, Folder -)
  - 004.004.4 Richard Nixon in Charlotte, NC in honor of Billy Graham (Tape 2 of 2; 1 of 2 copies), June 6, 1994 (Box 3, Folder -)
  - 004.004.4 Richard Nixon in Charlotte, NC in honor of Billy Graham (Tape 2 of 2; 2 of 2 copies, June 6, 1994 (Box 3, Folder -)
  - 004.005.4 Dick Cavett with Billy Graham and AOC Briefings, July 6, 1994; Beta (Box 3, Folder -)
  - 004.006.4 "60 Minutes" Charles Colson Interviews, May 26, 1974; Beta (Box 3, Folder -)
  - 004.009.1 With God On Our Side - Nixon, Silent Majority, June 21, 1996; BetaCam SP (Box 3, Folder -)
  - 004.007.4 Nixon Presidential Libraries - 10 Tapes Provided by Al Snyder, June 6, 1994; Beta (Box 4, Folder -)
  - 004.008.1 With God On Our Side - Graham and Caratt, June 21, 1996; Betacam SP (Box 4, Folder -)
  - 005.010.0 Untitled, undated; Beta (Box 4, Folder -)
  - 005.011.1 Untitled, undated; Beta (Box 4, Folder -)
  - 005.013.2 1957 Billy Graham Crusade, January 29, 1996; Beta (Box 4, Folder -)
  - 005.014.1 Mississippi Crusade, January 29, 1996; Beta (Box 4, Folder -)
  - 005.015.2A Youth for Christ Group Visits Europe (1951); Hour of Decision with guests Bill Bright and Don Moomaw (1953); Gospel in Song (1950); Part 1 of 2, January 29, 1996; Beta (Box 4, Folder -)
  - 005.015.2B Youth for Christ Group Visits Europe (1951); Hour of Decision with guests Bill Bright and Don Moomaw (1953); Gospel in Song (1950); Part 2 of 2, January 29, 1996; Beta (Box 4, Folder -)
  - 005.017.2 1950's DOC on Billy Graham, January 29, 1996; Beta (Box 4, Folder -)
  - 005.018.2 Billy Graham Crusade at Pittsburgh Stadium, January 29, 1996; Beta (Box 4, Folder -)
  - 005.019.2 Audio of Billy Graham News Conferences (1967 and 1963), January 29, 1996; Beta (Box 4, Folder -)
  - 005.020.2A Billy Graham Comments and Opinions; Part 1 of 2, January 29, 1996; Beta (Box 4, Folder -)
  - 005.020.2B Billy Graham Comments and Opinions; Part 2 of 2, January 29, 1996; Beta (Box 4, Folder -)
  - 005.021.2 Audio of Billy Graham Press Conference at Furman University in 1971, January 29, 1996; Beta (Box 4, Folder -)
  - 005.022.2 Billy Graham Center Archives; Part 1 of 2, undated; Beta (Box 4, Folder -)
  - 005.022.2 Billy Graham Center Archives; Part 2 of 2, undated; Beta (Box 5, Folder -)
  - 006.001.4 1974 Kanawha Textbook Controversy, undated; Beta (Box 5, Folder -)
  - 006.002.1 1974 Kanawha Country Textbook Controversy, June 24, 1996; Betacam SP (Box 5, Folder -)
  - 007.003.2 Robertson Interviews Jimmy Carter (1976), March 25, 1996; Beta (Box 5, Folder -)
  - 007.004.2 Bev La Haye on 700 Club, March 25, 1996; Beta (Box 5, Folder -)
  - 007.006.2 Reagan Inaugural and Election Returns (1980 and 1981), March 25, 1996; Beta (Box 5, Folder -)
  - 007.007.2 Schaeffer on 700 Club (1986), March 25, 1996; Beta (Box 5, Folder -)
  - 007.008.2 Koop on 700 Club, March 25, 1996; Beta (Box 5, Folder -)
  - 007.009.2 Tim Robertson Interviews Pat (May 17, 1988), March 25, 1996; Beta (Box 5, Folder -)
  - 007.012.2 Robertson on Bush's Campaign (1992), March 25, 1996; Beta (Box 5, Folder -)
  - 007.013.2 Pat Robertson Interviews J. Dobson (Part 1), March 25, 1996; Beta (Box 5, Folder -)
  - 007.014.2 Pat Robertson Interviews J. Dobson (Part 2), March 25, 1996; Beta (Box 5, Folder -)
  - 007.015.2 Robertson and Falwell Discuss Telescandals (March 27, 1987), April 12, 1996; Beta (Box 5, Folder -)
  - 007.016.2 Pat Robertson on the Berlin Wall (November 10, 1989), April 12, 1996; Beta (Box 5, Folder -)
  - 007.017.1 Alabama Textbook Case (March 5, 1987), May 15, 1996; Beta (Box 5, Folder -)
  - 007.018.2 Lee Atwater Interview on 700 Club (November 10, 1988), May 16, 1996; Beta (Box 5, Folder -)
  - 007.019.2 Tim Robertson Interviews Pa, May 16, 1996; Beta (Box 5, Folder -)
  - 008.001.4 Anita Bryant, undated; Beta (Box 6, Folder -)
  - 008.002.4 Anita Bryant - Gay Rights, undated; Beta (Box 6, Folder -)
  - 008.003.4 Anita Bryant - Gay Rights (1960s), undated; Beta (Box 6, Folder -)
  - 008.003.4 Untitled, undated; Beta (Box 6, Folder -)
  - 008.004.4 "Protect America's Children" Anti-Gay Ads, undated; Beta (Box 6, Folder -)
  - 009.003.2 Tape #1, part II: Sex Education, undated; Beta (Box 6, Folder -)
  - 009.004.2 Tape #2: Right Wing Sex Ed Convention; Governor Maddox Parade (1976), undated; Beta (Box 6, Folder -)
  - 009.005.2 1964 Republican National Convention ABC Selects (Part 1 of 2), undated; Beta (Box 6, Folder -)
  - 009.006.2 Goldwater at 1964 Republican National Convention (Part 2 of 2), undated; Beta (Box 6, Folder -)
  - 009.007.2 Tape #1: Washington Prayer Breakfast with LBJ and Billy Graham; Graham Preaching; Nixon Speech, undated; Beta (Box 6, Folder -)
  - 009.008.2 Tape #2: Goldwater Campaigns, undated; Beta (Box 6, Folder -)
  - 009.009.2 Tape #3: Goldwater at Conrad Hilton; Goldwater Whistle Stops/Rallies, undated; Beta (Box 6, Folder -)
  - 009.010.2 Tape #4: Barry Goldwater Speech at Madison Square Gardens; Religious Leaders; Nixon at Church; Christian Rock Bands (1972), undated; Beta (Box 6, Folder -)
  - 009.011.2 Tape #5: Bill Bright; Kanawha Controversy, undated; Beta (Box 6, Folder -)
  - 009.012.2 Tape #6: Kanawha Controversy Footage, undated; Beta (Box 6, Folder -)
  - 009.013.2 Tape #7: Kanawha Controversy Marches, undated; Beta (Box 6, Folder -)
  - 009.014.2 Tape #8: Kanawha Controversy Footage, undated; Beta (Box 7, Folder -)
  - 009.015.2 Tape #9: Kanawha Controversy Footage, undated; Beta (Box 7, Folder -)
  - 009.016.2 "With God On Our Side" ABC Off-Air 1964 Election Coverage, undated; Beta (Box 7, Folder -)
  - 009.017.5 20/20 Dr. Koop (May 14, 1987), May 14, 1987; VHS (Box 7, Folder -)
  - 009.018.1 Carter/Mondale; Media Preachers; Reagan Campaign; GOP Convention; The Born Again Right; Don White Interview, undated; Beta (Box 7, Folder -)
  - 009.019.1 Rally for Life by Religious Roundtable; Jerry Falwell Interview; Evangelical Rights; Reagan: First Press Conference as President-Elect, undated; Beta (Box 7, Folder -)
  - 009.020.1 Jimmy Carter Interviews; Jerry Falwell Interviews, undated; Beta (Box 7, Folder -)
  - 009.021.1 Reagan Speech to Fundamentalists; National Day of Prayer in the Rose Garden; Reagan Meets Religious Leaders; Carter/Mondale, undated; Beta (Box 7, Folder -)
  - 009.022.2 School Prayer Amendment; O'Connor Swear-In; Sen. Goldwater Interview, undated; Beta (Box 7, Folder -)
  - 009.023.2 Reagan Supreme Court Announcement; Jerry Falwell Clip Reel; Pro-Life Rally; Pro School Prayer Rally (Beta, DVD), undated (Box 7, Folder -)
  - 009.024.2 Pro School Prayer Rally; Evangelist James Robison; 1984 Democratic National Convention; Reagan and Tuition Tax Credits; 1984 Republican National Convention; 1984 Election Day Coverage, undated; Beta (Box 7, Folder -)
  - 009.025.2 Ronald Reagan Supreme Court Announcement, undated; Beta (Box 7, Folder -)
  - 009.026.2 Jesus Night Club (1971); Hollywood - A Mission Field for the New Jesus (1971); Nixon in Dallas (1970); Ford Speech to Realtors Organization (1973); Nixon Speaks at Prayer Breakfast (1970), February 8, 1996; Beta (Box 7, Folder -)
  - 009.027.2 Watergate Clips (1980), February 8, 1996; Beta (Box 7, Folder -)
  - 009.028.2 Untitled, February 9, 1996; Beta (Box 7, Folder -)
  - 009.029.2 Untitled, February 9, 1996; Beta (Box 7, Folder -)
  - 009.030.2 Nightline JUDD Student Demo; Ralph Reed Selects, Undated; Beta (Box 8, Folder -)
  - 009.031.2 Episode 3-4 Selections, Undated; Beta (Box 8, Folder -)
  - 009.032.2 "God On Our Side" Episode 5 (1 of 3), Undated; Beta (Box 8, Folder -)
  - 009.033.2 "God On Our Side" Episode 5 (2 of 3), Undated; Beta (Box 8, Folder -)
  - 009.034.2 "God On Our Side" Episode 5 (3 of 3), Undated; Beta (Box 8, Folder -)
  - 009.035.2 "God On Our Side" Episode 1: Nixon (February 5, 1970), March 5, 1996; Beta (Box 8, Folder -)
  - 009.036.2 Episode 5, March 5, 1996; Beta (Box 8, Folder -)
  - 009.037.2 Episode 5: Part A, March 6, 1996; Beta (Box 8, Folder -)
  - 009.037.2 Episode 5, March 6, 1996; Beta (Box 8, Folder -)
  - 009.038.1 Burden of a Secret, Undated; Beta (Box 8, Folder -)
  - 009.038.2 Episode 5, March 5, 1996; Beta (Box 8, Folder -)
  - 009.039.2 Jonestown Voter Apathy; School Prayer, March 5, 1996; Beta (Box 8, Folder -)
  - 009.040.2 Untitled, March 7, 1996; Beta (Box 8, Folder -)
  - 009.041.2 Untitled, March 7, 1996; Beta (Box 8, Folder -)
  - 009.042.2 Episode 5 - Selections and Graham Invocation, March 7, 1996; Beta (Box 8, Folder -)
  - 009.057.2 Episode 5: Robertson, 1988 (copy 1 of 2), 1988; Beta (Box 9, Folder -)
  - 009.058.2 Episode 5: Robertson, 1988 (copy 2 of 2), 1988; Beta (Box 9, Folder -)
  - 009.059.1 ABC News Bush Inauguration, April 26, 1996; Beta (Box 9, Folder -)
  - 009.060.2 Streakers (March 4, 1974), May 6, 1996; Beta (Box 9, Folder -)
  - 009.061.2 Robertson Campaign, May 6, 1996; Beta (Box 9, Folder -)
  - 009.062.2 Coverdell in Denver (1992 and 1993), May 6, 1996; Beta (Box 9, Folder -)
  - 009.063.2 Untitled, May 15, 1996; Beta (Box 9, Folder -)
  - 009.064.2 Billy Graham at Clinton Inauguration; Clarence Thomas, May 15, 1996; Beta (Box 9, Folder -)
  - 009.065.2 Karen Burns Abortion Poll, May 15, 1996; Beta (Box 9, Folder -)
  - 009.066.5 Day 1: Dr. James Dobson, September 21, 1995; VHS (Box 9, Folder -)
  - 009.066.5 "With God On Our Side" Day 1, Undated; Beta (Box 9, Folder -)
  - 009.071.2 1988 First Presidential Debate; Bush Campaign 1988; Assemblies of God: Swaggart; Children with AIDS, June 6, 1996; Beta (Box 9, Folder -)
  - 009.072.1 Ralph Reed; Alice Patterson, Undated; Beta (Box 9, Folder -)
  - 009.073.1 ABC News Clarence Thomas; Bush and Robertson, 1988 and 1991; Beta (Box 9, Folder -)
  - 009.077.5 This Week with David Brinkley (November 6, 1994), November 6, 1994; VHS (Box 9, Folder -)